# **CAREER PROFILE**

Experience in several programming languages for desktop, web, mobile and embedded.

Experience in Data Mining, and also Text Mining with focus in Author Profiling, using Python.

Interested in developing multiplatform systems and applications of Data and Text Mining.



### **Ruan Bahia**

**Software Developer** 

### **EDUCATION**

**BEng Computer Engineering** 2014 - 2020 Federal University of Vale do São Francisco (Univasf)

General knowledge in computer programming, with disciplines focused in C, C++ and Java. Concepts of software engineering developed through theoretical study and academic team projects. Computer architecture and networks knowledge, design and development of embedded systems projects during the course.

Participation in Embedded Systems Competitions promoted in SBESC 2016 and SBESC 2019, with team development of Radar<sup>3</sup> and busComfort projects. Artificial inteligence background with focus in Data Mining, participating in Data Mining Cup 2019.

Final course project research about Text Mining, producing the Research about the performance of Information Retrieval based features for Text Mining tasks.

- busComfort (https://gitlab.com/buscomfort/)
- DMC 2019 Participation (https://gitlab.com/jramorim1/dmc-2019---univasf/)
- Research on the performance of Information Retrieval based features for Text Mining tasks (https://github.com/ruanmed/tcc-ii-ir-featurestext-mining/)

- **J** +55 74 99930-30282 (tel:+55 74 99930-30282)
- ruanmed.github.io (http://ruanmed.github.io)

ruanmed (https://linkedin.com /in/ruanmed)

ruanmed (http://github.com /ruanmed)

ruanmed (http://gitlab.com/ruanmed)

#### **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese (Native) English (Professional)

#### **HOBBIES**

Ballroom dance CS:GO esport

(https://www.hltv.org)

# EXPERIENCES

**Software Developer** 

Hectares, Juazeiro (https://hectares.tech/)

2019 - present

PHP & Laravel back-end development, JavaScript & Vue front-end development. DevOps delivery in Digital Ocean droplets.

#### **Computer Engineering Intern**

2018 - 2019

Committee for Assessment (CPA/Univasf), Federal University of Vale do São Francisco, Juazeiro (http://www.cpa.univasf.edu.br/)

Subsidy for the actions of the commission which required specialized assistance in the area of Computer Engineering, including the development and maintenance of the commission's own systems, under supervision of Profa. Dra. Michelle Christini Araújo Vieira (http://lattes.cnpq.br/9372845638085633), then president of CPA, and under orientation of Prof. Dr. Max Santana Rolemberg Farias (http://docentes.univasf.edu.br/max.santana/).

A major contribution during this internship was the set of improvements made to the half-yearly evaluation system of CPA, which is a model-view-control web system programmed in Groovy and Java using a MySQL database.

Responsibilities during this internship included:

- Assistance in planning, organization and forwarding the committee's decisions;
- Implementation and maintenance of systems using HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript and SQL databases;
- Maintenance and update of CPA web systems;
- Advisement of CPA members by collecting necessary information to achieve CPA goals, assisting in the statistical treatment o the collected data;
- Organization and promotion of maintenance in the CPA databases, and collaboration in writing and formatting CPA reports.

## PROJECTS

Current projects in development are AgroPreços and Eloagro, applications developed in a team effort with the other founding members of Hectares.

Some previous projects include the contributions made creating and mantaining CAECOM-UNIVASF's website, also the project busComfort developed for SBESC 2019 Embedded Systems Competition.

busComfort (https://gitlab.com/buscomfort/) - Embedded system created for public transportation buses, focused in monitoring the comfort level during bus rides. Embedded modules programmed in C++ and Monitoring System mainly in JavaScript.

AgroPreços (https://hectares.tech/agroprecos/) - Single-page application exhibiting the commercial data of agricultural crops obtained from Brazil's agricultural supply centers (CEASAs). Developed using Quasar framework (Vue & JavaScript).

Eloagro (in development) - Platform for buyers and sellers of agricultural crops to negotiate fruits and vegetables. Android application developed using Quasar (Vue and JavaScript) with backend in Laravel (PHP).

CAECOM-UNIVASF Website (https://caecom.github.io/) - A website for the representative body of students of Univasf's Computer Engineering course. Developed using Jekyll static site generator with a custom template based in the free Moon theme for Jekyll.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY	
C++	
Python	
PHP & Laravel	
JavaScript & Vue	
HTML5 & CSS	
MySQL/MariaDB	
Elasticsearch	
ArangoDB	